Contact

ishristov@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ishristov (LinkedIn) github.com/ishristov (Other)

Top Skills

JavaScript
User Experience
Test Automation

Ivaylo Hristov

Front-end Engineer

Bulgaria

Summary

I have over 10 years of experience with front-end and backend development with a variety of environments, languages and libraries but now I'm mostly interested in React, Redux, Node.js and blockchains.

I always had passion about user experience and finding the best user flow but being a front-end engineer for a long time also taught me the importance of code reusability and consistency and that having a long term vision about the product is of the essence.

For about 4 years I've worked remotely with a company based in Mountain View, CA which later got acquired by VMware. Even though we had a 10h time difference that had never been a problem - not for me and not for anyone. Quite the opposite - that actually guaranteed that there would be someone working on the product almost constantly and showstoppers could be fixed before more people became blocked.

Working remotely helped me organise my time better and made me adapt to changes more easily and that's how I'd like to work in the future as well.

I am open for long-term and full-time contracting through my LLC company for easier management and I have valid B1/B2 visa for business trips to the USA if needed. I am also available for working on-site for the first weeks.

Experience with JS, ES6, React, Redux, SPA, Unit/UA testing (Selenium, Mocha, Tape, Expect), NPM/yarn, Grunt/Gulp/Babel, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, REST APIs, AJAX, jQuery, Git, Github, JIRA, HTML & CSS, CSS in JS, Responsive design, UX, handlebars, Virtual DOM.

Experience

Ivinity LLC Self Employed May 2018 - Present

Working on some personal projects and trying up some things with React, Redux and Node.js. Also published some open-sourced and free tools for the crypto community with Node.js and React.

Bracket Computing
Front-end Engineer (remote)
October 2014 - May 2018 (3 years 8 months)
Mountain View, CA

I was part of a small UI team and started as a remote contractor but ended up being an integral part of everything UI related. I was providing help by defining the style and the UX for future compatibility and consistency, mentored new additions to the team, communicated with PM on a daily basis to meet requirements and coded everything that needed coding on the UI and handled most of the automation tests with Selenium and unit tests.

We worked on a complex single page application that used a state based react-like framework and modularized structure, ES6 and numerous technologies from the js stack.

Mercury, Babel, Browserify, JSS, LoDash, NPM, Selenium, Tape, Git + Gerrit

Xentio Ltd.

Front-end Developer

August 2011 - May 2016 (4 years 10 months)

Participated in development teams and in direct customer communication for gathering requirements and clarifying UI design. Worked remotely with various clients and their team members for months and years with some.

I was developing the client side for the in-house product MammothDB (which was later acquired by MariaDB Foundation).

Another product that I've build was a multi-language multi-platform app built with PhoneGap for Android and iOS.

JS, jQuery, AJAX, HTML/Handlebars, CSS/SASS, Grunt, NPM, PhoneGap, Git, Jira

WebPresence Ltd. Lead Developer, Project Manager, SEO

August 2010 - August 2011 (1 year 1 month)

Building modern and search engine friendly websites (both front and back-end - HTML, CSS, JS, jQuery, AJAX, PHP, MySQL), using and integrating social media and APIs, communicating with potential clients, writing specifications, giving deadlines and setting prices.

Makstar Ltd.
PHP/MySQL Developer
March 2009 - April 2010 (1 year 2 months)

My part was developing a rich web-based system on PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, HTML & CSS for the company's clients from the medical sphere. With the system medical representatives were recording a large amount of information into multiple categories for their on-site visits and later it enabled complex queries and searches so the management could keep track of the representatives' performance.

Online Media Ltd.
Web Developer
February 2008 - August 2008 (7 months)

My first software job was to develop a shooter game in Flex (ActionScript OOP + MXML), consulting and helping for development of the other games and web portals of the company which were written primarily in PHP and MySQL.

Education

Telerik Academy
Certified, Mobile Applications Development Course

Telerik Academy
Certified, Web Client-Side Development Course

Telerik Academy
Certified, Web Front-End Development Course

University of National and World Economics Bachelor, Economics, Real Estates · (2007 - 2011)